<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<root>
    
<name>David Hwang</name>
<address1>4152 Verdugo Rd.</address1>
<address2>Los Angeles, CA 90065-3821</address2>
<phone>(818) 688-1517</phone>
<email>d.hw4ng@gmail.com</email>
<website></website>

<!--- This is a guide     0123456789012345678901234567890123456789012345678901234567890123456789012345678901234567 -->
<sec name="Experience" desc="">
	<!-- Smartify -->
	<loc value="Smartify, Inc." city="Pasadena, CA">
		<pos value="Software Engineer" date="August 2012 - Present">
			<desc type="">Developed features, wrote tests, debugged, maintained a promotions/sweepstakes platform consisting of a public-facing widget, an analytics dashboard, and internal configuration tools (all using Ruby on Rails).</desc>
			<desc type="">Implemented an analytics workflow which processes 100M+ rows of data gathered from promotions/sweepstakes using Amazon Redshift and Elastic MapReduce.</desc>
			<desc type="">??? Widget Refactoring + AJAX</desc>
			<desc type="">??? Authentication schemes</desc>
			<desc type="">??? HubSpot integration, mailing list integrations</desc>
			<desc type="">??? Dev ops type of stuff</desc>
			<desc type="">Automated retrieval of Facebook likes data from 50K platform users a day via Facebook's Graph API.</desc>
			<desc type="">Resolved web application performance issues including high database cpu utilization, slow query performance, and slow web server response times.</desc>
		</pos>
	</loc>
	<!-- CLICC -->
	<loc value="UCLA College Library Instructional Computing Commons" city="Los Angeles, CA">
		<pos value="Programming Specialist" date="September 2010 - August 2012">
			<desc type="">Implemented a RESTful web service with Java/JAX-RS which manages study room reservations.</desc>
			<desc type="">Developed a PHP web application for IT helpdesk staff to visualize where devices are located.</desc>
			<desc type="">Maintained several PHP web applications, including an outfacing informational public website, an internal staff website, and a tool to reserve group study rooms.</desc>
		</pos>
		<pos value="Laptop Administrative and Technical Assistant" date="June 2009 - January 2010">
			<desc type="">Assisted in overseeing laptop lending operations, consisting of about 200 Apple MacBook laptops.</desc>
			<desc type="">Supervised and trained five student helpdesk workers with the goal of maintaining hardware in student computer labs and laptop lending operations.</desc>
		</pos>
		<pos value="Student Helpdesk Specialist" date="July 2008 - June 2009" skip="true">
			<desc type="">Maintained hardware in student computer labs of about 160 desktop computers and 11 printers.</desc>
		</pos>
		<pos value="Consultant" date="September 2007 - June 2008" skip="true">
			<desc type="">Proctored student computer labs; troubleshooted PC and Mac problems; provided customer service.</desc>
		</pos>
	</loc>
	<!-- HP -->
	<loc value="Hewlett-Packard Company" city="San Diego, CA">
		<pos value="Intern" date="June 2011 - September 2011">
			<desc type="">Improved usability of HP Wall Art's internal site/CMS by implementing batch upload of large files (upwards of 50MB) and AJAX-driven user interfaces, using Ruby on Rails and HTML5 File API.</desc>
			<desc type="">Set up an OAuth provider and added RESTful endpoints for an API intended for third-party eCommerce integrations with HP Wall Art.</desc>
		</pos>
	</loc>
	<!-- Zobrist -->
	<loc value="Zobrist Consulting Group, Inc." city="Van Nuys, CA">
		<pos value="Intern" date="June 2010 - September 2010">
			<desc type="look above">Developed a fully-functional prototype of an e-commerce product search page using the Apache Solr search platform and AJAX, supporting multi-tier faceted navigation by category, search bar autocomplete, and spellchecking.</desc>
		</pos>
	</loc>
	<!-- Reader -->
	<loc value="UCLA Department of Mathematics" city="Los Angeles, CA">
		<pos value="Reader" date="January 2007 - June 2007">
			<desc type="">Graded assignments for introductory C++ (PIC 10A) and multivariable calculus (Math 32B).</desc>
		</pos>
	</loc>
</sec>

<sec name="Skills" desc="">
	<text header="Languages">Proficient in Ruby/Ruby on Rails and SQL. Prior experience with C, Java, C++, JavaScript, PHP, Python, and MATLAB.</text>
	<br/>
	<text header="Software">GNU/Linux, Mac OS X, Git, MySQL, MongoDB, Hive, and Apache Solr.</text>
</sec>

<sec name="Education" desc="">
	<loc value="University of California, Los Angeles" city="Los Angeles, CA">
		<pos value="M.S., Computer Science" date="September 2010 - March 2012">
			<desc type="">Overall GPA: 3.933.</desc>
			<desc type="">Relevant Coursework: Advanced Operating Systems, Computer Systems Architecture, Data Mining, Databases and Knowledge Bases, Web Information Systems, Computer Security</desc>
		</pos>
		<pos value="B.S., Mathematics of Computation" date="September 2005 - June 2009">
			<desc type="">Overall GPA: 3.554.</desc>
			<desc type="">Relevant Coursework: Algorithms and Complexity, Programming Languages, Operating Systems Principles, Database Systems, Software Engineering, Networking</desc>
		</pos>
	</loc>
</sec>

<sec name="Projects" desc="">
	<pos value="Intelligent Switching between ZeroMQ and TCP/IP for Data Streams" date="December 2011 - March 2012">
		<desc type="">Experimented with Unix socket programming and an alternative sockets library (ZeroMQ) to improve network throughput for data streams. Final project for M.S. degree.</desc>
	</pos>
	<pos value="Anisotropic Diffusion of Hyperspectral Imagery" date="March 2009 - June 2009">
		<desc type="">Studied the effects of applying certain differential equations upon images for image segmentation using MATLAB.</desc>
	</pos>
	<pos value="Video Tracking" date="July 2007 - September 2007">
		<desc type="">Implemented an adaptive foreground detection algorithm for video in a group summer research project at UCLA Mathematics, using MATLAB and C++ with the OpenCV computer vision library.</desc>
	</pos>
</sec>

</root>

